Sean Fuhrman

seanfuhrman.com github.com/Sean-Fuhrman sean@seanfuhrman.com 908-285-3692

Fourth-year Computer Engineering student continuing at University of California, San Diego for a master's in Data Science & Machine Learning. Over a decade of programming experience, with a focus on 2+ years in Python/PyTorch for building machine learning models. Skilled in web development (HTML/CSS/JavaScript) and well-versed in Deep Learning, Predictive Modeling, Algorithms, and Object Oriented Programming.

EDUCATION

• University of California, San Diego

San Diego, CA

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering; Major GPA: 3.9; GPA: 3.77;

Sept. 2020 - Present

- Relevant Coursework: Object Oriented Programming, Advanced Data Structures & Algorithms, Computer Architecture, Probabilistic Machine Learning, Web Client Languages.
- Awards: Provost Honors
- o Extracurriculars: Data Science Student Society, Ski & Snowboard Team

SKILLS

- Programming Languages: Python; Javascript; HTML/CSS; Java; C++/C; Bash;
- Frameworks/Packages: PyTorch; NumPy; Pandas; Matplotlib; scikit-learn; Git; Jupyter; React; Node.js;

EXPERIENCE

• Art of Problem Solving

San Diego, CA

Software Engineering Intern

June 2023 - August 2023

- Implemented 50+ printable engines in React with Node.js backend, automating the conversion of online math problems into printable formats.
- Led a comprehensive exploration of prompt engineering techniques, successfully integrating Large Language Models for automatic language translation.
- Produced a working proof-of-concept demonstrating the effectiveness of large language models in language translation, while preserving custom mark-up language syntax.
- Collaborated with design and development teams to ensure the successful integration of print functionality.

• System Energy Efficiency Lab - University of California, San Diego

San Diego, CA

Research Assistant

July 2022 - Present

- Assisted with research on hyper-dimensional computing algorithms and its use for energy-efficient processing-in-memory machine learning.
- Authored research paper on combining metric learning with hyper-dimensional computing algorithm to increase model accuracy and error robustness.
- o Developed PyTorch model to simulate machine-learning algorithm running on error-prone analog hardware.
- Created non-binary hyper-dimensional computing algorithm utilizing differentiable soft quantization techniques to ensure accurate gradient descent.

Projects

• Shazam 2.0

github.com/jasminelo2020/shazam2.0

Data Science Student Society

- Developed a Convolutional Neural Network (CNN) based music genre classification model trained on the Million Song Dataset.
- Achieved an exceptional accuracy of 99.6% on a dataset of over 200,000 songs and 15 genres.
- Utilized PyTorch to build efficient training pipeline, incorporating hyperparameter tuning and train/test/validate split to prevent overfitting
- Presented our methods and findings at project showcase; poster available here.

• Personal Website

• Designed and programmed my own resume website at seanfuhrman.com

• Room Automation System

- o Designed, prototyped, and debugged microcontroller system designed to act as "assistant" via voice commands
- $\circ\,$ Capable of controlling lights, telling the weather, and playing music